Theodore K. Rabb Papers on the National Council for History Education: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Dept. of Rare Books and Special Collections.
Theodore K. Rabb Papers on the National Council for History Education
2000-2012
MC260
Princeton University. Library. Dept. of Rare Books and Special Collections. Seeley G. Mudd Manuscript Library. Public Policy Papers. 65 Olden Street Princeton, New Jersey 08540 USA
2.0 linear feet 2 boxes
Rabb, Theodore K., 1937-
This collection is closed until 2022.
This collection was a gift of Theodore K. Rabb in May 2012. The accession number associated with this gift is ML.2012.024.
- Electronic Records, 2000-2012
- Documents on the History of the National Council for History Education (NCHE), 2006-2012; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- History of NCHE - Elaine, 2008; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Position Papers, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Employee Handbook, 2007; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- History Matters, 2007-2009; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Fundraising, 2007-2008; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous, 2007; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- National Assessment of Educational Progress (NAEP), 2007; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- National Board for Professional Teaching (NBPT), 2007; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- National History Center, 2007 June; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Gilda-Lehrman Foundation Clearinghouse, 2007; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Historically Speaking, 2007; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Lobbying/Christina Anderson, 2007-2009; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Letter Writing Campaign, 2007-2008; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Board Election, 2000-2007; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Board/Officers, 2006-2008; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Board Minutes, 2007; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Cathy Gorn / Williamsburg Meeting, 2007; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Board Meeting, 2007 November; 2 Folders (Box 1)
- Louisville 2008 Conference, 2007-2008; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Louisville 2008 Board Meeting, 2007-2008; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Board Meeting - NYC, 2008; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Boston 2009 Conference, 2007-2009; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Boston Board Meeting, 2009 March; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Committees, 2006-2008; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Governance Committee, 2007-2008; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Board Nominations Committee, 2007-2008; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Nominating Committee, 2007-2008; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Conferences Committee, 2007-2008; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Publications Committee, 2007-2008; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Search Committee, 2007; 2 Folders (Box 1)
- State/National Relations Committee, 2004-2008; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Teaching American History (TAH) Committee, 2007-2008; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- World History Committee, 2007-2009; portion of 1 box (Box 1)
- Office Space, 2008-2009; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Washington, DC Move, 2007; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Reforming History Education Conference, 2007; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Retreat of US Senate Chiefs of Staff, Philadelphia PA, 2007; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- NCHE No Child Left Behind (NCLB) legislation, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- NCLB -- David McCullough efforts, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- NCHE Presentation of Senator Byrd Award to Robert Byrd, Washington DC, 2008; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- NCHE Advisory Board, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- American Institute of History Education (Kevin Brady), undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- NCHE Website, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- NCHE State Councils, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Mellon Colloquium, St. Louis MO, 2008; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- NCHE Trademark, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Lapham's Quarterly -- Peter Struck, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- NCHE Financial Problems of Spring, 2009; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Rabb Resignation, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- The History Foundation, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Fritz Fischer, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Laura Fisher, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Byron Hollinshead, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Phyllis Krutsch, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Elaine Wrisley Reed, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Michelle Unguratt, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Laura Wakefield, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Sam Wineburg, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Anthony DiBattista, Treasurer (Budget), undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Betty Franks, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Lesley Hermann (Gilder-Lehrman Foundation), undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Margaret Miller (staff member), undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Joseph Ribar (staff member), undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Cynthia Stout (Executive Director), undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Denice Toyias (Assistant Executive Director), undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Eric Foner and Leon Litvak, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence (e.g. Justice Kennedy), undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)
- Print-outs of electronic e-mails, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 2)